<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>EasyList</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://easylist.github.io/feeds/articles.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://easylist.github.io/</id><updated>2015-08-19T07:47:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Issues with Yavli Advertising</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2015/08/19/issues-with-yavli-advertising.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-19T07:47:00+02:00</published><author><name>fanboy</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2015-08-19:2015/08/19/issues-with-yavli-advertising.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some sites have been insisting in showing &amp;quot;Native Advertising&amp;quot; namely a organisation called Yavli advertsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yavli advertising has kept changing their domains and elements to avoid being caught in EasyList and this become too frequent. So we have had to take extraordinary steps to avoid the list being flooded with hundreds of Yavli domains. The only option was to block third-party images and scripts on these domains who use Yavli advertising:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;activistpost.com addictinginfo.org alfonzorachel.com allenbwest.com allenwestrepublic.com
americanlivewire.com askmefast.com bidnessetc.com bulletsfirst.net chacha.com christianpost.com
christiantoday.com clashdaily.com classicalite.com comicallyincorrect.com comicbookmovie.com
conservativebyte.com conservativevideos.com cowboybyte.com crossmap.com dailycaller.com
dailyheadlines.net dailysurge.com dccrimestories.com designntrend.com digitaljournal.com
drhotze.com enstarz.com explosm.net gamerant.com ... (Full list of domains affected in the post)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While it does resolve 90% of the Yavli issues, the downside of this change for the web developers that it will break any analytics used on the site. If you're a web developer of any of these sites, we're happy to remove any filters related to your site if Yavli Advertising is removed from your site.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll endeavor to keep up the blocking of Yavli Advertising. So if there are any sites we've haven't fixed or major issues on these selected sites, let us know.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyList"></category></entry><entry><title>Known issues of EasyList Dutch</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2013/09/14/known-issues-of-easylist-dutch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-09-14T18:40:00+02:00</published><author><name>Famlam</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2013-09-14:2013/09/14/known-issues-of-easylist-dutch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post lists the known issues of EasyList Dutch (previously DutchAdblockList), in Dutch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;De volgende problemen op Nederlandstalige websites zijn bekend&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probleem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Het is niet mogelijk om spoilers te openen op het forum van fok.nl&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Betrokken domein&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;forum.fok.nl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oplossing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;U kunt dit oplossen door advertenties toe te staan op deze pagina's door het volgende filter toe te voegen: &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;&amp;#64;&amp;#64;||forum.fok.nl/topic/$document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probleem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Spellen op spelletjes.nl en spel.nl starten vertraagd&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Betrokken domeinen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spelletjes.nl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spel.nl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Op deze websites voor spelletjes starten de spellen pas na enkele tientallen seconden. Dit komt omdat de website op de achtergrond denkt dat er een advertentie gedurende die tijd bezig is, en het spel pas start als die tijd over is. De advertentie is natuurlijk geblokkeerd, maar de tijd kan niet overgeslagen worden.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oplossing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Geen. Wacht tot het spel vanzelf start&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probleem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Sommige advertenties in videos en games kunnen niet geblokkeerd worden&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;In videos/games van enkele domeinen kunnen videoadvertenties niet geblokkeerd worden omdat de video/game dan zelf niet meer af kan spelen&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Betrokken domeinen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;538.nl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;herhaling.nl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kinderspelletjes.nl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ongein.nl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;radio10.nl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;radioluisteren.fm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;radioveronica.nl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rtl7darts.nl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;skyradio.nl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tvgids.tv&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;twentefans.nl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vmma.be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;voetbalprimeur.nl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vtm.be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oplossing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Geen. Wacht tot de advertentie afgelopen is&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probleem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Een lege popup verschijnt op tvgids.nl&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Op tvgids.nl zal bij het laden van de pagina een lege popup verschijnen, waarin oorspronkelijk advertenties stonden. Deze kan niet in de lijst geblokkeerd worden, omdat dan ook enkele legitieme onderdelen van de site niet meer functioneren.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Betrokken domein&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tvgids.nl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oplossing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Wilt u de popup toch blokkeren, voeg dan zelf het volgende filter toe: &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;tvgids.nl###simplemodal-container,#simplemodal-overlay&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probleem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;De melding &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Ad block gedetecteerd, de mogelijkheid tot het afspelen van de video wordt uitgeschakeld&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Op enkele domeinen wordt &lt;em&gt;in FireFox&lt;/em&gt; de melding getoond dat er een adblocker gedetecteerd is. Helaas detecteren deze websites niet of Adblock Plus actief is, maar alleen of het geïnstalleerd is. Daardoor helpt ook het uitschakelen van ABP op deze websites niet.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Betrokken domeinen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kijk.nl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nu.nl (de sportvideos)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oplossing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Dit probleem vindt alleen in FireFox plaats. U kunt de videos in een andere browser bekijken.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andere problemen gevonden op Nederlandstalige websites? Geef dit dan door in het &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/viewforum.php?f=100"&gt;forum&lt;/a&gt; van EasyList Dutch of stuur een email naar het adres in de &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist-downloads.adblockplus.org/easylistdutch.txt"&gt;filterlijst&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="known issues"></category><category term="EasyList Dutch"></category></entry><entry><title>EasyList Czech and Slovak and Latvian List are now affiliated subscriptions</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2013/05/28/easylist-czech-and-slovak-and-latvian-list-are-now-affiliated-subscriptions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-05-28T15:07:00+02:00</published><author><name>MonztA</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2013-05-28:2013/05/28/easylist-czech-and-slovak-and-latvian-list-are-now-affiliated-subscriptions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://code.google.com/p/adblock-czechoslovaklist/"&gt;EasyList Czech and Slovak&lt;/a&gt;, written by tomasko126, as well as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://latvian-list.site11.com/"&gt;Latvian List&lt;/a&gt;, written by anonymous74100, have now become officially affiliated with EasyList and are also a recommended subscriptions for Czech and Slovak and Latvian users. The subscriptions are listed on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/"&gt;EasyList homepage&lt;/a&gt;, from where they may be viewed or installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to provide feedback, including reporting adverts or problems, please use the Adblock Plus issue reporter or open a topic in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/viewforum.php?f=99"&gt;EasyList forums&lt;/a&gt; for Latvian List. For EasyList Czech and Slovak you can use the issue reporter as well or its &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://code.google.com/p/adblock-czechoslovaklist/issues/list"&gt;bug tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Affiliated filter lists"></category><category term="EasyList"></category></entry><entry><title>EasyList merges with Fanboy's List</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2013/05/17/easylist-merges-with-fanboy-s-list.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-05-17T07:29:00+02:00</published><author><name>MonztA</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2013-05-17:2013/05/17/easylist-merges-with-fanboy-s-list.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Easy team is very happy to announce today that both major ad blocking lists, EasyList and Fanboy's List, become one list! Also, EasyPrivacy and Fanboy's Tracking List were merged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this change all users will have a consistent Internet browsing experience and will no longer have to bother whether they have to choose EasyList or Fanboy's List or which one of them is better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fanboy, who has many years of experience in ad blocking, is a gain for the Easy project and will from now on be the main author. Welcome to the team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fanboy's Annoyance List was already included in the EasyList repository some weeks ago. Also, a new filter list solely for blocking social media integration, Fanboy's Social Blocking List, was created and is officially &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/en/features#socialmedia"&gt;featured on the Adblock Plus features page&lt;/a&gt;. It was adapted from the Annoyance List which means you do not need it if you already have Fanboy's Annoyance List.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You do not need to do anything to get the new list(s), everything will be done automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any issues, please &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/"&gt;report them in our forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyList"></category><category term="EasyPrivacy"></category></entry><entry><title>Anti-adblock guide for site admins</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2013/05/10/anti-adblock-guide-for-site-admins.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-05-10T15:28:00+02:00</published><author><name>MonztA</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2013-05-10:2013/05/10/anti-adblock-guide-for-site-admins.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Most sites do not mind if users have adblocking software installed in their browser. There are however a couple of sites that take counter measurements, trying to convince users to disable their adblockers. Our &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/en/policy"&gt;policy&lt;/a&gt; states the following about those so-called anti-adblock measurements: &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Anti-Adblock should only be challenged if the system limits website functionality or causes significant disruption to browsing&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;. Since this can be interpret in numerous ways, here's a more detailed explanation for webmasters about what we allow or disallow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;This is what we allow and/or require from anti-adblock measurements:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It must use small, static images and/or text only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The font and markup must be similar to the other parts of the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The text must be polite and understandable, or at least in the same tone as the other parts of the website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It must be clear that the message is shown because the user is using adblocking software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It must not interrupt the normal reading flow of the page content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It must be clear that any action requested in the anti-adblock message, like disabling the adblocking software, whitelisting your site or asking a donation as a replacement for the ads, is completely voluntarily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It may suggest disabling adblockers entirely, but if it does, it must also include detailed and easy-to-read instructions to disable them on your domain only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the user clicks an anti-adblock message, more content may be shown (including overlays, animated images and all otherwise forbidden content types, like plugins), provided they can be closed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user must be the only one in control of the filters required for the purpose of the anti-adblock message. It must not be possible for external sources to add, modify or remove any rules remotely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;This however is what we do not allow:&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animations (including changing text messages), sounds and other content that will constantly distract the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content that uses plug-in resources or frames.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redirects (automatic page forwarding) and pop-ups to a different page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content that overlaps the normal page content or prevents the normal reading flow in any other way, like messages in the middle of a text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content with a height over 100px and a combined area larger than 105,000px. This includes the size of unnecessary empty areas caused by the message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content for which it is not immediately clear it's targeted to users of adblocking software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measurements that limit the access to the site and/or cause annoying side effects (like additional delays) and/or prevent normal content to be shown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that isn't too hard, is it? If you follow these guidelines, we're all happy. We (the list authors), because we don't have to add or adjust rules for your site. The visitor, because (s)he won't be the victim of terrible anti-adblock measurements. And the site admins, because they don't have to adjust their site every time we block their message, while still being able to tell users about their adblockers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are just two more side notes that should be mentioned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your anti-adblock message does not follow the guidelines, or there is discussion about its compliance, it is up to the list author(s) to determine if we block it or leave it as it is. When your anti-adblock message is being blocked specifically, while it's following all guidelines, please leave a notification in our &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/"&gt;forums&lt;/a&gt; or send an email to &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:easylist.subscription&amp;#64;gmail.com"&gt;our email address&lt;/a&gt;; if we agree, it'll be unblocked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In case your anti-adblock message is being removed by a filter that is also used to block or hide ads or other content that should be blocked anywhere else, it will not be whitelisted, even if you perfectly follow all guidelines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyList"></category><category term="EasyList Dutch"></category><category term="EasyList Germany"></category><category term="EasyList Italy"></category></entry><entry><title>Ads caused by malware or adware extensions or plugins</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2013/03/09/ads-caused-by-malware-or-adware-extensions-or-plugins.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-03-09T13:50:00+01:00</published><author><name>MonztA</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2013-03-09:2013/03/09/ads-caused-by-malware-or-adware-extensions-or-plugins.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;French version: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adblock-listefr.com/Adware"&gt;adblock-listefr.com/Adware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ads caused by malware or adware &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://support.mozilla.org/kb/find-and-install-add-ons-add-features-to-firefox"&gt;extensions&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://support.mozilla.org/kb/use-plugins-play-audio-video-games"&gt;plugins&lt;/a&gt; on your computer will not be fixed by EasyList. If you arrived at this page for other reasons than curiosity about this blog, it is likely that a list author send you here because your computer is infected with such an extension or plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please check all your extensions and plugins by disabling them one-by-one, restarting the browser each time after you did so, until the strange behaviour or ads are gone. In that case, the extension/plugin you disabled last is bad and should be removed. You can remove suspicious/unwanted extensions/plugins directly of course. Virus scanners often do not find such extensions or plugins!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's also &lt;strong&gt;recommended to scan your computer&lt;/strong&gt; with any of these removal tools, even if you have found the responsible extension or plugin in the previous step to make sure there are no left-overs on your system:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bleepingcomputer.com/download/adwcleaner/"&gt;AdwCleaner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.malwarebytes.org/products/malwarebytes_free"&gt;Malwarebytes' Anti-Malware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.safer-networking.org/dl/"&gt;Spybot - Search &amp;amp; Destroy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, to &lt;strong&gt;prevent such issues in the future&lt;/strong&gt;: the next time you install an extension/plugin, consider if you really need it and if the site looks &lt;strong&gt;trustworthy&lt;/strong&gt;. That will save you a lot of trouble in the future and likely keeps your browsing faster too. Apart from that, &lt;strong&gt;always download software from the software developers' website&lt;/strong&gt;. Also, when asked so during the installation of any kind of software, do not install any additional toolbars, coupon notifiers, shopping widgets, etc. they offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional information can be found in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://support.mozilla.org/kb/troubleshoot-firefox-issues-caused-malware"&gt;this troubleshooting guide from Mozilla Support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Adblock Plus"></category><category term="known issues"></category></entry><entry><title>Liste AR is now an affiliated subscription</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2013/02/17/liste-ar-is-now-an-affiliated-subscription.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-17T16:20:00+01:00</published><author><name>MonztA</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2013-02-17:2013/02/17/liste-ar-is-now-an-affiliated-subscription.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;To be honest, it is for quite a while already but I somehow missed to announce it properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://code.google.com/p/liste-ar-adblock/"&gt;Liste AR&lt;/a&gt;, written by smed79 and Liste FR author Crits, has now become officially affiliated with EasyList and is also a recommended subscription for Arabic users. The subscription is listed on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/"&gt;EasyList homepage&lt;/a&gt;, from where it may be &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist-downloads.adblockplus.org/Liste_AR.txt"&gt;viewed&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="abp://subscribe/?location=https://easylist-downloads.adblockplus.org/Liste_AR.txt&amp;amp;title=Liste%20AR"&gt;installed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is recommended to use it together with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/#listefr"&gt;Liste FR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to provide feedback about Liste AR, including reporting adverts or problems, please use the Adblock Plus issue reporter or open a topic in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/viewforum.php?f=98"&gt;EasyList forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Affiliated filter lists"></category><category term="EasyList"></category></entry><entry><title>Ads on hulu.com are no longer blocked</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2012/10/24/ads-on-hulu-com-are-no-longer-blocked.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-24T10:02:00+02:00</published><author><name>MonztA</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2012-10-24:2012/10/24/ads-on-hulu-com-are-no-longer-blocked.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Video ads on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.hulu.com/"&gt;hulu.com&lt;/a&gt; show up before the actual video starts.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Affects:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.hulu.com/"&gt;hulu.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;any other page where Hulu videos are embedded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cause:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Hulu videos on external sites are embedded in a HTML frame (example: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/10/17/jon-stewart-scoffs-at-paul-ryan-soup-kitchen_n_1973566.html"&gt;huffingtonpost.com&lt;/a&gt;). While the video ads on Hulu itself can still be blocked (a countdown shows up instead of a video ad), embedded videos on external sites will no longer play unless videa ads are allowed. This forced us to add specific whitelists for these ads.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution (Firefox only!):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Unfortunately, there is no way to block the ads on Hulu and allow them on external sites as the latter are embedded in a HTML frame. If you do not watch Hulu video on external sites, you can disable the whitelists and still watch videos on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.hulu.com/"&gt;hulu.com&lt;/a&gt; without ads. Here is a step-by-step instruction how to disable them:&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on the &amp;quot;ABP&amp;quot; icon in Firefox (it is most likely in the left corner at the bottom) and choose &amp;quot;Filter preferences...&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog-images/abp_preferences.png"&gt;this button on the right&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on the &amp;quot;Find&amp;quot; button that appeared on the top.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type &lt;strong&gt;hulu.com/published&lt;/strong&gt; and disable these two exception rules &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#64;&amp;#64;||hulu.com/published/*.flv&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#64;&amp;#64;||hulu.com/published/*.mp4&lt;/strong&gt; by unticking them like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog-images/abp_preferences_2.png"&gt;shown in this screenshot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close the filter preferences window of Adblock Plus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</summary><category term="Adblock Plus"></category><category term="EasyList"></category><category term="known issues"></category></entry><entry><title>Aktuelle Probleme mit Videoportalen</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2012/10/07/aktuelle-probleme-mit-videoportalen.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-07T14:22:00+02:00</published><author><name>MonztA</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2012-10-07:2012/10/07/aktuelle-probleme-mit-videoportalen.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Werbung taucht vor dem oder im Video auf.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Betroffene Seiten:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.clipfish.de/"&gt;Clipfish.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.spiegel.tv/"&gt;Spiegel.tv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.spiegel.de/"&gt;Spiegel.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nowtv.de/rtl"&gt;RTL NOW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nowtv.de/vox"&gt;Vox NOW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nowtv.de/superrtl"&gt;Super RTL NOW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nowtv.de/rtl2"&gt;RTL 2 NOW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nowtv.de/rtlnitro"&gt;RTL Nitro NOW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nowtv.de/ntv"&gt;n-tv NOW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.t-online.de/tv/"&gt;T-Online.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://web.de/"&gt;web.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gmx.net/"&gt;gmx.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://home.1und1.de/"&gt;1und1.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sueddeutsche.de/"&gt;sueddeutsche.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.n-tv.de/"&gt;n-tv.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.golem.de/"&gt;golem.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pcgames.de/"&gt;pcgames.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pcgameshardware.de/"&gt;pcgameshardware.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.videogameszone.de/"&gt;videogameszone.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.gamesaktuell.de/"&gt;gamesaktuell.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.gamezone.de/"&gt;gamezone.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.buffed.de/"&gt;buffed.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.4players.de/"&gt;4players.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ursache:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Die betroffenen Seiten haben eine Erkennung eingebaut, die überprüft, ob die Werbung geladen wurde oder nicht.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lösung:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Eine richtige Lösung gibt es aktuell nicht. Man muss die Werbung zulassen, um das eigentliche Video zu sehen. Andernfalls kann man das Video nicht sehen.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
</summary><category term="Adblock Plus"></category><category term="known issues"></category></entry><entry><title>Softonic Toolbar, PriceGong und Babylon entfernen</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2012/08/20/softonic-toolbar-pricegong-und-babylon-entfernen.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-08-20T10:36:00+02:00</published><author><name>MonztA</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2012-08-20:2012/08/20/softonic-toolbar-pricegong-und-babylon-entfernen.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Da viele User von unerwünschten Inhalten, die auf die Softonic Toolbar, PriceGong und Babylon zurückzuführen sind, berichten, habe ich eine Anleitung zusammengestellt, wie man diese Programme entfernen kann. Adblock Plus kann dies nämlich nicht entfernen. Die unerwünschten Inhalte äußern sich wie folgt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog-images/toolbar2.png"&gt;search.softonic.com ist als Startseite festgelegt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog-images/toolbar2.png"&gt;search.softonic.com ist als Suchmaschine in der Suchleiste festgelegt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;search.softonic.com wird ebenfalls geöffnet, wenn man einen neuen Tab öffnet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vornehmlich auf Shoppingportalen erscheinen &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog-images/toolbar1.png"&gt;oben und unten rechts in Mozilla Firefox Meldungen, dass Gutscheine für diesen Shop bereitlägen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog-images/toolbar2.png"&gt;&amp;quot;More For You&amp;quot;-Fenster unten links in Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog-images/toolbar1.png"&gt;&amp;quot;WindowShopper&amp;quot;-Overlay auf Amazon.de&lt;/a&gt; (ggf. auch auf anderen Seiten)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anleitung: Softonic Toolbar, PriceGong und Babylon entfernen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schließen Sie zunächst Mozilla Firefox und den Internet Explorer (falls geöffnet). Kopieren Sie daher die nachfolgende Anleitung in ein Word-Dokument/eine Textdatei und speichern Sie sie auf dem Desktop ab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gehen Sie über den &amp;quot;Start&amp;quot;-Button in die Systemsteuerung und klicken dann auf &amp;quot;Programme und Funktionen&amp;quot; (Windows Vista/7) bzw. auf &amp;quot;Software&amp;quot; (Windows XP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deinstallieren Sie dort die &amp;quot;Softonic Toolbar for IE&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;PriceGong&amp;quot; unf ggf. &amp;quot;Babylon&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am Ende der Deinstallation der &amp;quot;Softonic Toolbar for IE&amp;quot; wird man gefragt, ob man die derzeitige Startseite und Sucheinstellungen behalten möchte. Verneinen Sie dies (diese Aktion hat nur auf den Internet Explorer Einfluss).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starten Sie Mozilla Firefox, klicken Sie auf den &amp;quot;Firefox&amp;quot;-Button oben links (bzw. &amp;quot;Extras&amp;quot; in der Menüleiste), dann auf &amp;quot;Add-ons&amp;quot; und schließlich auf &amp;quot;Erweiterungen&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Klicken Sie rechts neben &amp;quot;Softonic.com&amp;quot; auf &amp;quot;Deinstallieren&amp;quot; und starten Sie Firefox neu. Wiederholen Sie dies für die &amp;quot;Babylon&amp;quot;-Erweiterung.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Klicken Sie in der Suchleiste oben rechts auf das linke Lupen-Symbol und wählen dann &amp;quot;Suchmaschinen verwalten...&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Klicken Sie auf &amp;quot;Search the web (Softonic)&amp;quot; und anschließend auf &amp;quot;Entfernen&amp;quot;. Wiederholen Sie dies ggf. für &amp;quot;Search the web (Babylon)&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geben Sie &amp;quot;&lt;a class="reference external" href="about:config"&gt;about:config&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; (ohne &amp;quot; &amp;quot;) in die Adressleiste ein, bestätigen Sie mit Enter und klicken Sie auf die &amp;quot;Ich werde vorsichtig sein, versprochen!&amp;quot;-Schaltfläche.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geben Sie &amp;quot;softonic&amp;quot; (ohne &amp;quot; &amp;quot;) in das Suchfeld ein und setzen Sie alle Einträge mit einem Rechtsklick und dann auf &amp;quot;Zurücksetzen&amp;quot; zurück. Schneller geht es, wenn man rechtsklickt und dann die R-Taste auf der Tastatur drückt. Wiederholen Sie dies für den Begriff &amp;quot;babylon&amp;quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lade Sie sich AdwCleaner (Direktdownload: &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://general-changelog-team.fr/fr/downloads/finish/20-outils-de-xplode/2-adwcleaner"&gt;http://general-changelog-team.fr/fr/downloads/finish/20-outils-de-xplode/2-adwcleaner&lt;/a&gt;) herunter, schließen Sie Firefox und starten Sie das Programm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Klicken Sie auf &amp;quot;Search&amp;quot; und schließen Sie danach die Textdatei.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Klicken Sie dann auf &amp;quot;Delete&amp;quot; (der Computer wird danach automatisch neugestartet).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Klicken Sie auf den &amp;quot;Start&amp;quot;-Button und dann auf &amp;quot;Ausführen...&amp;quot; oder führen Sie die Tastenkombination Windows-Taste + R aus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geben Sie &amp;quot;%temp%&amp;quot; (ohne &amp;quot; &amp;quot;) in das Feld ein, bestätigen Sie mit Enter und löschen Sie alle Ordner und Dateien, die Sie in dem Fenster sehen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vermutlich waren diese Programme installiert, da Sie Mozilla Firefox oder vielleicht auch ein anderes Programm von der Softonic-Seite heruntergeladen haben und bei der Installation die Softonic Toolbar, PriceGong oder Babylon standardmäßig ausgewählt waren. &lt;strong&gt;Bitte laden Sie Programme - egal ob Mozilla Firefox oder andere Software - immer von der Herstellerseite herunter.&lt;/strong&gt; Im Falle von Mozilla Firefox ist es &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mozilla.com/"&gt;mozilla.com&lt;/a&gt; oder auch &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.firefox.com/"&gt;firefox.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Adblock Plus"></category><category term="EasyList Germany"></category><category term="known issues"></category></entry><entry><title>EasyList Italy update</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2011/11/15/easylist-italy-update.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-11-15T14:58:00+01:00</published><author><name>MonztA</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2011-11-15:2011/11/15/easylist-italy-update.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EasyList Italy subscription has been &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/subscriptionlist/rev/feb0e50aa762"&gt;granted recommended status&lt;/a&gt; in Adblock Plus, which means that it will be the default selection for Italian users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to provide feedback about EasyList Italy, including reporting adverts or problems, please use the Adblock Plus issue reporter or &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/viewforum.php?f=96"&gt;open a topic in the EasyList forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyList"></category><category term="EasyList Italy"></category></entry><entry><title>Announcing EasyList Italy</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2011/09/27/announcing-easylist-italy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-09-27T20:19:00+02:00</published><author><name>MonztA</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2011-09-27:2011/09/27/announcing-easylist-italy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although EasyList author Khrin started to develop EasyList Italy just two weeks ago, it already has a considerable amount of filters and it is now ready to go live. The subscription is designed as a supplement for Italian-language websites and is now listed on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/"&gt;EasyList homepage&lt;/a&gt;, from where it may be &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist-downloads.adblockplus.org/easylistitaly.txt"&gt;viewed&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="abp://subscribe?location=https://easylist-downloads.adblockplus.org/easylistitaly.txt&amp;amp;title=EasyList%20Italy&amp;amp;requiresLocation=https://easylist-downloads.adblockplus.org/easylist.txt&amp;amp;requiresTitle=EasyList&amp;quot;"&gt;installed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to provide feedback about EasyList Italy, including reporting adverts or problems, please use the Adblock Plus issue reporter or &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/viewforum.php?f=96"&gt;open a topic in the EasyList forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyList"></category><category term="EasyList Italy"></category></entry><entry><title>Two years, seventeen days, three hours and five minutes</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2011/09/10/two-years-seventeen-days-three-hours-and-five-minutes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-09-10T12:13:00+02:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2011-09-10:2011/09/10/two-years-seventeen-days-three-hours-and-five-minutes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It has been two years, seventeen days, three hours and five minutes since I became involved with EasyList by creating &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/memberlist.php?mode=viewprofile&amp;amp;u=1101"&gt;an account&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/"&gt;EasyList forums&lt;/a&gt;. When I joined, I did not expect that I would ever rise to my present position of lead EasyList and Privacy author, forum administrator and all the other roles that I have accumulated in &lt;a class="reference external" href="/author/michael.html"&gt;my EasyBlog profile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was chance that lead to my first major breakthrough: only three months after I had joined the forum, I was granted contributor status and thereby discovered, via a topic in the private forum, that Ares2 was officially struggling to maintain the subscriptions (my 500 posts over my first three months on the forum had &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; to do with this). Wladimir was, at the time, reorganising the Adblock Plus repositories anyway and offered a Mercurial repository to Ares2, which was eventually accepted. The question then arose who would assist Ares2, which I replied to with the following post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I would be willing to help, although I appreciate that I am somewhat of a novice in comparison to the other members of the private forum.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;Michael&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite my acknowledgment of my limited involvement with EasyList, my application was accepted, along with Erunno's, and by early December I was actively committing changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becoming the lead author was also a matter of being in the right place at the right time. By the end of April I was effectively the only active EasyList author, to the extent that I complained, via private message to Erunno and Ares2, that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I signed up for a group project, not a one man band.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;Michael&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I received assistance from Erunno, Ares2 found himself unable to continue to run EasyList and in June he therefore offered me the position of lead author, which I readily accepted. It was also acknowledged that we need more help, and three people were offered authorship at the time: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/memberlist.php?mode=viewprofile&amp;amp;u=333"&gt;MonztA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/memberlist.php?mode=viewprofile&amp;amp;u=1400"&gt;Khrin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/memberlist.php?mode=viewprofile&amp;amp;u=1488"&gt;Famlam&lt;/a&gt;, of whom MonztA and Khrin immediately accepted and soon &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/blog/brief-easylist-status-update"&gt;took on their new positions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the peculiar circumstances that lead me to my position, I decided to develop EasyList further, redesigning &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/"&gt;the website&lt;/a&gt;, which had not been significantly altered since Rick was the EasyList author, and adding &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog"&gt;this blog&lt;/a&gt;. I added groups to the forum to more clearly identify significant people, such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/memberlist.php?mode=group&amp;amp;g=56"&gt;contributors&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/memberlist.php?mode=group&amp;amp;g=59"&gt;subscription authors&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/memberlist.php?mode=group&amp;amp;g=58"&gt;EasyList authors&lt;/a&gt;, and added the private &amp;quot;EasyList Authors' Forum&amp;quot; to reduce the excessive use of private messages by authors. I have also been one of two authors of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/subscriptionlist/"&gt;SubscriptionList&lt;/a&gt; and helped to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/en/filter-cheatsheet"&gt;develop the Adblock Plus documentation&lt;/a&gt; and check the English localisation of Adblock Plus - I am responsible for &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/adblock-plus/"&gt;the description of Adblock Plus on the Mozilla Add-ons domain&lt;/a&gt;. More recently, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog/2011/09/09/new-easylist-author:-famlam"&gt;Famlam has taken up my offer to become an author&lt;/a&gt; and I have developed &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/viewtopic.php?t=8765"&gt;FOP (Filter Orderer and Preener)&lt;/a&gt;, which automatically sorts and commits changes to Adblock Plus subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is not to say that I have no regrets about my time with the project - I have certainly made some significant mistakes, including &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/viewtopic.php?t=5577"&gt;committing a rule that would have broken a very large number of websites&lt;/a&gt; had the filter not been spotted quickly and being overly antagonistic to an important company - but that I am generally proud of my involvement with EasyList.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most significant change to the EasyList project while I have been the lead author is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog/2011/02/10/easyprivacy-tracking-protection-list"&gt;to make the subscriptions available as Tracking Protection Lists (TPLs)&lt;/a&gt; for Microsoft's Internet Explorer using a script I developed, but which was later significantly improved by Wladimir; EasyPrivacy TPL now accounts for &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog/2011/09/01/easylist-statistics:-august-2011"&gt;just over half of all EasyPrivacy downloads&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are my memories of EasyList - my reminisces. But I now need to move to the present and to reality. Over my two years with the project I have been successful in real life, but have realised that the resulting changes will reduce my level of my involvement for the foreseeable future to such a low standard as to do a disservice to the community. EasyList needs stability - there has been approximately one lead author a year since &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/blog/sad-news"&gt;Rick's unfortunate death in 2009&lt;/a&gt; - and I am unable to provide it. As I hinted in a hidden message in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog/2011/09/01/easylist-statistics:-august-2011"&gt;a recent blog post&lt;/a&gt;, I am therefore stepping down from all of my roles associated with EasyList and Adblock Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/memberlist.php?mode=viewprofile&amp;amp;u=333"&gt;MonztA&lt;/a&gt; has kindly agreed to take over the role of lead EasyList and EasyPrivacy author (he is already the lead EasyList Germany author), effective immediately. He has been writing subscriptions for at least twice as long as I've even been involved with EasyList and I know that he already has plans to continue to develop the project. I wish him and the community the best of luck and thank the numerous people (too many to list here) who have supported me as an author. But now I must leave. After two years, seventeen days, three hours and five minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyList"></category><category term="EasyPrivacy"></category></entry><entry><title>New EasyList author: Famlam</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2011/09/09/new-easylist-author:-famlam.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-09-09T15:02:00+02:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2011-09-09:2011/09/09/new-easylist-author:-famlam.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to announce that we have a new author for EasyList, EasyPrivacy and EasyList Germany: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/memberlist.php?mode=viewprofile&amp;amp;u=1488"&gt;Famlam&lt;/a&gt;. He has been a member of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/"&gt;EasyList forum&lt;/a&gt; for nearly a year and a half and is already a contributor to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://code.google.com/p/adblockforchrome/"&gt;AdBlock for Chrome&lt;/a&gt;, one of several advert blocking add-ons for Chrome that use the EasyList subscriptions. He was officially granted the status of EasyList author yesterday evening and I hope that you will welcome him into his new role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would also encourage anyone else interested in becoming an author for EasyList, EasyPrivacy or EasyList Germany to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/en/about"&gt;contact the project&lt;/a&gt;. As I noted in a recent article on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog/2011/09/01/easylist-statistics:-august-2011"&gt;EasyList usage and downloads&lt;/a&gt;, we have very few authors relative to the millions of users of the subscriptions and would be glad of additional assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyList"></category><category term="EasyPrivacy"></category><category term="EasyList Germany"></category></entry><entry><title>EasyList Statistics: August 2011</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2011/09/01/easylist-statistics:-august-2011.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-09-01T12:00:00+02:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2011-09-01:2011/09/01/easylist-statistics:-august-2011.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Looking back, it has been &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/viewtopic.php?t=679"&gt;a long time since&lt;/a&gt; anyone has evaluated or released the statistics for the EasyList subscriptions, so I thought that, as August has just eneded, it might be time to estimate exactly how many users there are of the filter lists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I am aware that most people are interested simply in the user estimates, I should start by explaining how the statistics are gathered for the users of EasyPrivacy and any other privacy conscious individuals. When a browser connects to a web server, it automatically sends information to request a copy of, in this instance, a text file. This request includes the user agent, which for Firefox states the name of the operating system (although this information is not present in my statistics) and the version of the browser. The Adblock Plus website, like so many others, logs these requests with the time and date the request was made. These logs are then analysed by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://awstats.sourceforge.net/"&gt;AWStats&lt;/a&gt;. No active tracking scripts have been installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there is a lot of information, calculating the number of users of the EasyList subscriptions cannot provide a complete picture for a variety of reasons. Adblock Plus updates subscriptions between four and six days after they were last updated. However, if a user does not use a browser for a day, then an update will be delayed for a day, up to ten days after a subscription was last updated. This being August, many people are likely to be on holiday, which means that the subscription updates are likely to be less frequent than my assumed value of five days. It is also possible, but extremely unlikely, that results may be overestimated as a result of many people forcing a download from the Adblock Plus preferences window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viewing the statistics at the time this algorithm was implemented, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/blog/downloading-a-file-regularly-how-hard-can-it-be"&gt;Wladimir hoped that the changes would prevent a “Monday peak”&lt;/a&gt; from overloading the server, the result of office workers all updating on Monday morning if the five day interval passed over the weekend. However, it is clear that there are a number of users of the subscriptions who do not have a recent version of Adblock Plus installed. Using the four full weeks of August 2011 as an example, Mondays show on average 12% more downloads than would be expected (week total / 7), ranging from 110.8% to 118.5% of the expected traffic. In contrast, downloads tended to tail off as the week progressed, the most marked drop being on Saturdays and Sundays, with an average of 92% of the expected traffic each day. This ranged from a low of 91.6% on Saturday 13 August to a weekend high of 95.8% on Sunday 28 August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In spite of the variation based on week day the total number of downloads per week was fairly stable: in order, each week achieved 98.1%, 99.0%, 100.7% and 102.2% of expected traffic, the initial low results likely the results of holidays without computers and therefore without updates to EasyList.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, however, it is time to answer the big question: how many people actually use the subscriptions? These values were calculated by taking the total number of downloads in a month, dividing the resulting total by thirty one to find the average number per day and then multiplying by five, as this would be, if everyone used their browser daily (which they don't), the average update period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going through the subscriptions, it is no surprise that &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/#easylist"&gt;EasyList&lt;/a&gt; has the largest user base. Taking into account all combined subscriptions, versions and variations, such as the one with element hiding rules, the one without rules for adult websites and relevant tracking protection lists, we find that there were seventy three million downloads of the file in August, suggesting that there are &lt;strong&gt;twelve million users&lt;/strong&gt;, of whom 99% use Adblock Plus filter format. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/#easylistgermany"&gt;EasyList Germany&lt;/a&gt; has also been popular, with two and a half million users (99.9% Adblock Plus format), as has &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/#easyprivacy"&gt;EasyPrivacy&lt;/a&gt;, despite the comparatively paltry total of &amp;quot;just&amp;quot; half a million users. However, unlike EasyList and EasyList Germany, which have seen little usage as Tracking Protection Lists, just over half of the users of EasyPrivacy use &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog/2011/02/10/easyprivacy-tracking-protection-list"&gt;EasyPrivacy TPL&lt;/a&gt;, its popularity likely due to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://ie.microsoft.com/testdrive/Browser/TrackingProtectionLists/"&gt;Microsoft's promotion of the list&lt;/a&gt;, which we are very grateful for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, it is possible to put these values in perspective: how dominant is EasyList as an Adblock Plus subscription? Looking at &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://addons.mozilla.org/statistics/addon/1865"&gt;the public statistics page for the add-on&lt;/a&gt; and ignoring the recent erroneous readings, we find that there are twelve and a half million users of Adblock Plus. Taking into account the usage of AdBlock for Chrome and Adblock Plus for Chrome, which according to user agents accounts for, at most, 15% of installations, we find that 80% of people using Adblock Plus use EasyList as a primary subscription. This is despite the random selection of EasyList or Fanboy's List for a new English language user. I would attribute this popularity to historical reasons (people installed Adblock Plus when EasyList was the only recommended subscription for English language users); the large number of recommended supplementary subscriptions, including &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/#easylistgermany"&gt;EasyList Germany&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://code.google.com/p/ruadlist/"&gt;RU AdList&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://adblock-listefr.com/"&gt;Liste FR&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://code.google.com/p/adblock-chinalist/"&gt;ChinaList&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="#id2" id="id1"&gt;[*]&lt;/a&gt;, to name but a few, which are selected automatically when the subscription and browser languages match; and its position as a fallback subscription: if the browser language does not match any recommended subscription, EasyList is automatically installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the minor subscriptions also deserve a mention. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/#easylistnoelemhide"&gt;EasyList without element hiding&lt;/a&gt; has accumulated around seven thousand users, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog/2011/05/30/announcing-easyadult"&gt;EasyList without rules for adult sites&lt;/a&gt; has over two thousand users and EasyPrivacy without international filters has just over one thousand users. Finally, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/viewtopic.php?t=8505"&gt;EasyTest&lt;/a&gt;, an EasyList supplement used for examining filters known to cause problems on websites, has accumulated just 33 users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is great variation in the usage of the EasyList subscriptions, the statistics emphasise the great responsibility that we authors have - a minor mistake can quickly affect thousands of people. I would therefore appeal to anyone who has made it to the final paragraph to consider getting involved with the project to assist the very few authors we have - even suggesting rules for problematic sites helps us to reduce the time it takes to commit a fix. Regardless of this challenge, I am optimistic:  provided the requisite bandwidth is made available (4.2 TB was required this month for the Adblock Plus version of EasyList alone), I see no reason why the project should not continue to be successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id2" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label" /&gt;&lt;col /&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="#id1"&gt;[*]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;I am not going to discuss the usage of the affiliated subscriptions as I do not have the statistics for the files hosted third-party, but the subscription authors are welcome to write their own analysis with the assistance of statistics for the EasyList mirrors - you should know how to access the logs, if not, please private message me.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyList"></category><category term="EasyPrivacy"></category><category term="EasyList Germany"></category></entry><entry><title>What is acceptable first-party tracking?</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2011/08/31/what-is-acceptable-first-party-tracking.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-08-31T18:17:00+02:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2011-08-31:2011/08/31/what-is-acceptable-first-party-tracking.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although all third-party tracking is blocked outright by EasyPrivacy, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/en/policy#easyprivacy"&gt;the subscription's policy&lt;/a&gt; is slightly more lenient with first-party tracking, specifying that that items should be blocked only if they &amp;quot;collect a significant amount of personal data&amp;quot;. As the wording is ambiguous, I have decided to convey my interpretation of the policy with regard various pieces of information available from the user and whether the subscription should specifically prevent the collection of such data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IP address and user agent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Although this information is recorded in system logs, the details make users identifiable, making this information personal. I would therefore suggest that EasyPrivacy should continue to regard the first-party collection of such data as unacceptable and prevent it being sent to any additional systems on the domain wherever possible.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Screen resolution, colour depth and browser plugins&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;This information is not located in the system logs and pertains only to the user's system. I would therefore suggest that tracking this information is unacceptable.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time zone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Time zone provides a very approximate location of the user, and I would therefore suggest that this information should be classified as personal and prevented from being collected where possible.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;If the language is that of the website the I do not have an issue with the information being collected, as it is about the site rather than user. However, to record the value set in the browser oversteps the mark in my opinion.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JavaScript status&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;I would regard the JavaScript status as generic information provided that trackers do not attempt to determine the reason why scripts are unavailable, and I would therefore suggest collecting this type of information is acceptable.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advert blocking status&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;There is no intrinsic issue with detection of advert blocking software (we do not object to websites adding unobtrusive messages to their pages specifically for users of such programs). Therefore, provided that no detailed information such as the name of program responsible is collected, I would regard this type of tracking as acceptable.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page status&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Information about the page itself, such as the address or whether the content has loaded, is not personal information, and I would therefore suggest that collecting information about the site status is acceptable.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Random&amp;quot; numbers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;I have no issue with genuinely random numbers being generated on each page or the use of a timestamp. However, I would not consider it acceptable to use a number to track the user's visit trail around a website without their consent, as this would make the value little better than an IP address.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Object tracking (e.g. using Flash or Java to track users)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;In the vast majority of instances objects are unnecessary alternatives to other methods of tracking, such as JavaScript. Furthermore, these objects can set cookies that cannot be easily controlled by the browser. I would therefore regard the collection of information using plug-ins as unacceptable in practically all circumstances.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyPrivacy"></category></entry><entry><title>The definition of "advert" and link exchange policy</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2011/07/11/the-definition-of-advert-and-link-exchange-policy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-11T15:14:00+02:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2011-07-11:2011/07/11/the-definition-of-advert-and-link-exchange-policy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The basic principle of EasyList is that its &amp;quot;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/en/policy#easylist"&gt;filters must remove adverts&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;. However, several discussions, usually with website owners, have highlighted an obvious issue: &amp;quot;advert&amp;quot; has not been precisely defined. A &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://forums.lanik.us/viewtopic.php?t=8578"&gt;topic was therefore opened&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://forums.lanik.us/viewforum.php?f=95"&gt;new EasyList policy forum&lt;/a&gt; and culminated in the definition of an advert as &amp;quot;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://forums.lanik.us/viewtopic.php?t=8578#p34875"&gt;the promotion of third party content in return for goods or services&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;. This has several implications, as explained below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&amp;quot;Promotion&amp;quot;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Specifying that an advert must promote means that a factual link (e.g. &amp;quot;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/"&gt;Adblock Plus&lt;/a&gt; is a Firefox add-on.&amp;quot;) cannot be an advert as it lacks a marketing aspect. Furthermore, an independent review is also unable to be an advert because it critically examines all facets of the content, not just the positive aspects.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&amp;quot;Third-party&amp;quot;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;The aim of a website is to entice people to read more of its content, which visitors presumably desire to do, as indicated by their presence on the domain; they should therefore not be hindered in doing so by a filter subscription. Whether websites are third-party or first-party (what happens if one person owns two domains?) is a question for the EasyList authors to consider.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&amp;quot;... in return for goods or services&amp;quot;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;An important question that has been raised is whether an advert requires the exchange of money, to which I would respond that it is not an essential element. Money may be one of the goods supplied, but there may also be services provided in return. Therefore a link to, say, a web host would be removed if this is a sponsored link required as a provision of service, but not if the description is merely factual, as this would not be promotion.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://forums.lanik.us/viewtopic.php?t=8578#p34880"&gt;definition includes link exchange schemes&lt;/a&gt;, whereby websites reciprocally exchange logos and links to the other domains for no other benefit, which Tarun, a website owner himself, claimed was not worthwhile removing given the large number of domains which use the link exchanges and their comparatively unobtrusive nature. After &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://forums.lanik.us/viewtopic.php?t=8601"&gt;further discussion&lt;/a&gt; it was agreed that, provided links exchanges are unobtrusive and free of any tracking parameters, they will not be specifically removed by EasyList.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyList"></category></entry><entry><title>Advertisers' and tracking companies' websites</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2011/07/01/advertisers-and-tracking-companies-websites.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-01T18:44:00+02:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2011-07-01:2011/07/01/advertisers-and-tracking-companies-websites.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Some websites relating to advertisers and tracking companies (predominantly the former) do not function correctly when EasyList or EasyPrivacy are enabled respectively.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Affects:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://google.com/adsense/"&gt;Google AdSense&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.google.com/ads/"&gt;Google Ads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adwords.google.com/"&gt;Google Adwords&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.google.com/analytics/"&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.buysellads.com/"&gt;Buysellads.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://partnernet.amazon.de/gp/associates/join/compensation.html"&gt;amazon PartnerNet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.affili.net/"&gt;affilinet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://adbase.co/"&gt;AdBase&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://sellercentral.amazon.com/"&gt;sellercentral.amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://sellercentral-europe.amazon.com/"&gt;sellercentral-europe.amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://sellercentral.amazon.co.uk/"&gt;sellercentral.amazon.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://advertise.ubermedia.com/"&gt;UberAds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.advert.ly/"&gt;Advert.ly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.facebook.com/"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.scarlet-clicks.info/"&gt;ScarletClicks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adwolf.eu/"&gt;adWolf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sophus3.com/"&gt;sophus3&lt;/a&gt; (+ .de, .es, .fr &amp;amp; .it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adclick.lv/"&gt;AdClick.lv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://468x60.lv/"&gt;468x60.lv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://textads.lv/"&gt;textads.lv&lt;/a&gt; (+ .nl &amp;amp;.biz)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.admarvel.com/"&gt;AdMarvel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adnetwork.net/"&gt;AdNetwork.Net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adpartner.com/"&gt;adpartner.com&lt;/a&gt; (+ .si, .nl, .com.pl, .fi ...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adresult.ch/"&gt;adresult.ch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adriver.ru/"&gt;adriver.ru&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://adsbox.lv/"&gt;adsbox.lv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.microad.jp/"&gt;microad.jp&lt;/a&gt; (+ .co.id, .vn &amp;amp;.co.jp)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.adbanner.gr/"&gt;adbanner.gr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.advert.com/"&gt;advert.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.openx.com/"&gt;OpenX.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.text-link-ads.com/"&gt;text-link-ads.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bluekai.com/"&gt;bluekai.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.conversionruler.com/"&gt;conversionruler.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.haveamint.com/"&gt;haveamint.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other domains are also likely to be affected and will be listed as they are reported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cause:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;EasyList is intended to remove adverts, just as EasyPrivacy is intended to remove tracking. The subscriptions often include general rules to remove the unwanted content and also selectively block domains that exclusively serve such items. However, as these filters are often and unsurprisingly activated by websites belonging to advertisers and tracking companies, some parts of the domain may fail to function correctly.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/en/policy"&gt;Subscription policy&lt;/a&gt; is that it is not worthwhile to resolve issues on domains belonging to advertisers and tracking companies, beyond requiring that filters blocking an entire domain only apply on third-party websites, as we believe that very few users regularly visit such websites. However, it is possible to disable Adblock Plus on the affected website using the option in the menu activated by clicking on the icon in the browser.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 30/05/2013:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;The EasyList authors decided to fix broken sites of advertisers and tracking companies as from today if they approach us personally via &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:easylist.subscription&amp;#64;gmail.com"&gt;e-mail&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://forums.lanik.us/"&gt;forum&lt;/a&gt;. If the whitelists allow ads or tracking, they will either be adjusted if possible or removed again.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyList"></category><category term="EasyPrivacy"></category><category term="known issues"></category></entry><entry><title>Cashback schemes and EasyPrivacy</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2011/06/09/cashback-schemes-and-easyprivacy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-06-09T18:35:00+02:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2011-06-09:2011/06/09/cashback-schemes-and-easyprivacy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Some cashback systems do not function correctly when EasyPrivacy is enabled.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Affects:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.extrarebates.com/"&gt;http://www.extrarebates.com/&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/viewtopic.php?t=8502"&gt;view report&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other cashback systems are also likely to be affected and will be listed as they are reported.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cause:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Cashback websites work by either setting a third party cookie or directing people to a special address to inform the shopping website that the user is eligible for a discount. Shopping websites then need to be able to view the information to identify the user and reduce the item cost if applicable. However, EasyPrivacy is designed to prevent such details being collected; the shopping website therefore lacks the information to suggest that a special offer should be applied and charges to full price instead of the discounted rate.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;I have &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog/2010/10/29/filter-subscriptions-and-important-internet-transactions"&gt;previously recommended&lt;/a&gt;, and would still advocate, that Adblock Plus should be disabled on important websites and when shopping. This will ensure that subscriptions do not interfere with the purchasing of goods and will therefore prevent issues from arising with cashback schemes. However, regardless of whether or not advert blocking software is installed, I would always recommend that you confirm the price of an item before paying.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyPrivacy"></category><category term="known issues"></category></entry><entry><title>DutchAdblockList and ABPindo updates</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2011/06/06/dutchadblocklist-and-abpindo-updates.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-06-06T18:06:00+02:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2011-06-06:2011/06/06/dutchadblocklist-and-abpindo-updates.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/en/"&gt;DutchAdblockList&lt;/a&gt;, authored by Famlam, a contributor to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/gighmmpiobklfepjocnamgkkbiglidom"&gt;Adblock for Chrome&lt;/a&gt;, has been a recognised subscription for a little over a year now. However, we have been impressed by the filter list, which caters for Dutch-language domains, and are therefore please to announce our affiliation with the subscription, which may be either &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist-downloads.adblockplus.org/easylistdutch.txt"&gt;viewed&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="abp:subscribe?location=https://easylist-downloads.adblockplus.org/easylistdutch.txt&amp;amp;title=EasyListDutch&amp;amp;requiresLocation=https://easylist-downloads.adblockplus.org/easylist.txt&amp;amp;requiresTitle=EasyList"&gt;installed&lt;/a&gt; from the homepage. Furthermore, after a review of the combination by myself and Fanboy, the subscription has been &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/subscriptionlist/rev/bb2ca98db299"&gt;granted recommended status&lt;/a&gt; in Adblock Plus, which means that it will be the default selection for Dutch users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to provide feedback about DutchAdblockList, including by reporting adverts or problems, please use the Adblock Plus issue reporter or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://forums.lanik.us/viewforum.php?f=100"&gt;open an issue in the Google project page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog/2010/12/23/abpindo-is-now-an-affiliated-subscription"&gt;affiliated&lt;/a&gt; subscription &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://abpindo.blogspot.com/"&gt;ABPindo&lt;/a&gt;, designed for Indonesian-language websites, has also been &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/subscriptionlist/rev/b49564d983ae"&gt;granted recommended status recently&lt;/a&gt; and now has its own &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://forums.lanik.us/viewforum.php?f=94"&gt;section in the EasyList forums&lt;/a&gt; for feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Adblock Plus"></category><category term="Affiliated filter lists"></category><category term="EasyList"></category></entry><entry><title>Announcing EasyAdult</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2011/05/30/announcing-easyadult.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-05-30T17:30:00+02:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2011-05-30:2011/05/30/announcing-easyadult.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There has recently been considerable discussion among contributors to the EasyList project about the status of rules for adult domains in the subscription. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/en/policy#easylist"&gt;EasyList policy&lt;/a&gt; has been that &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog/2010/12/12/an-important-reminder-about-adult-websites"&gt;filters for such websites have been excluded from the subscription&lt;/a&gt;, with users referred to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fanboy.co.nz/"&gt;Fanboy's Adult / Dating List&lt;/a&gt; as a supplement to the filter list. This policy resulted from two factors: adult domains were thought to require too much work to adequately filter and the belief that the subscription would be unfairly biased towards such websites, affecting user experience due to an increase in the download size and processing required. However, Ares2 has recently advanced arguments that have not only persuaded contributors that the EasyList project should filter adult domains, but that these rules should be included in the default version of EasyList.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that there are a lot more EasyList authors we are able to expand our website coverage without negatively affecting existing domains. Furthermore, as Ares2, MonztA, and Khrin are all keen to add rules for adult domains, there is the motivation among developers to support EasyList on adult websites. It was therefore agreed that there should be at least a supplement available with all such filters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason that it was ultimately decided that rules for adult domains should be located in the default installation of EasyList is that the majority of users are simply not aware of customisation options and do not install the supplementary subscriptions that they need. While we acknowledge that many users of Adblock Plus do not visit adult domains, we believe that a large enough proportion do to warrant the default inclusion of rules for adult domains in EasyList. While there are likely to be a lot of filters for adult domains, the actual effect that the additional rules will have on subscription performance is negligible due to optimisations in Adblock Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors responsible for the EasyAdult section (Ares2, MonztA and Khrin) have therefore started to add filters to the repository; this section is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/easylist/rev/7bf4ac3950f5"&gt;now included in the default installation of EasyList&lt;/a&gt;. Any tracking items found on adult domains will be added to EasyPrivacy, although it is not anticipated that there many specific services will be discovered. However, EasyAdult is far from finished, and we would therefore welcome contributions in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://forums.lanik.us/viewforum.php?f=64"&gt;filter suggestions&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://forums.lanik.us/viewforum.php?f=62"&gt;false positive reports&lt;/a&gt; forums, preferably with an indication that the referenced domain contains adult content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users who would prefer not to have filters for adult domains may &lt;a class="reference external" href="abp://subscribe?location=https://easylist-downloads.adblockplus.org/easylist_noadult.txt&amp;amp;title=EasyList%20without%20rules%20for%20adult%20sites"&gt;install&lt;/a&gt; the variant &amp;quot;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist-downloads.adblockplus.org/easylist_noadult.txt"&gt;EasyList without adult filters&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; from the homepage.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyList"></category></entry><entry><title>Affiliation with ChinaList</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2011/05/08/affiliation-with-chinalist.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-05-08T18:52:00+02:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2011-05-08:2011/05/08/affiliation-with-chinalist.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/p/adblock-chinalist/"&gt;ChinaList&lt;/a&gt; is a familiar subscription to many Adblock Plus users, being one of the oldest filter lists for the extension and recommended for Chinese language domains. Although the subscription was previously independent, they recently decided to switch to being a supplement to EasyList, at which point we approached the authors to discuss the possibility of affiliating with them. After a few minor adjustments in line with our policy, we are now pleased to announce the affiliation and that combination subscriptions are now available and listed on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/#chinalist"&gt;our homepage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to provide feedback about ChinaList, including by reporting adverts or problems, please use the Adblock Plus issue reporter or submit suggestions in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://groups.google.com/group/adblock-chinalist"&gt;their forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Affiliated filter lists"></category><category term="EasyList"></category></entry><entry><title>Giorgio Maone, NoScript.net and FlashGot.net</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2011/04/25/giorgio-maone-noscript-net-and-flashgot-net.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-04-25T18:46:00+02:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2011-04-25:2011/04/25/giorgio-maone-noscript-net-and-flashgot-net.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Some adverts are not blocked by EasyList on Giorgio Maone's add-on websites.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Affects:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;ul class="first last simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://noscript.net/"&gt;http://noscript.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://flashgot.net/"&gt;http://flashgot.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cause:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;At the end of February the EasyList project were privately notified that there remained some unblocked adverts on Giorgio Maone's add-on websites which were slightly different to items usually blocked by the subscription. Instead of being an external file or text links, the images were encoded and saved in an embedded stylesheet, which meant that the only way to remove them would be to use element hiding rules to collapse the unwanted area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aware that the difficulty of filtering out images encoded in this method (&lt;strong&gt;data:image&lt;/strong&gt;), I &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/forum/viewtopic.php?t=6968"&gt;requested support for the format in the Adblock Plus forums&lt;/a&gt;, referring merely to &amp;quot;a familiar website&amp;quot; instead of explicitly naming the problematic domains. However, as such encoded images are not easily distinguished because they have no file name, it was decided that it might be better to wait and see whether the rules that &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://code.google.com/p/ruadlist/"&gt;RUAdList&lt;/a&gt; implemented were successful. While, under normal circumstances, filters would be added immediately, prior events (see &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/blog/attention-noscript-users"&gt;Wladimir's&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hackademix.net/2009/05/04/dear-adblock-plus-and-noscript-users-dear-mozilla-community/"&gt;Giorgio's&lt;/a&gt; blogs) led the authors to concur that &amp;quot;we shouldn't start a cat and mouse game again&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This issue was then pushed to the back of our minds until the topic was &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/forum/viewtopic.php?f=1&amp;amp;t=7356"&gt;publicly raised in the Adblock Plus forums&lt;/a&gt; on the ninth of April, with a user asking Giorgio the same question that he asked us: why were adverts still present on the NoScript website? Although Hubird, the Adversity author, explained that he believed that &amp;quot;the NoScript developer actively makes it difficult for subscription authors to remove ads from his site (changing site design in an effort to thwart attempts)&amp;quot;, an assertion which MonztA, an EasyList author, agreed with, Giorgio responded with the following post, which I have included in its entirety to avoid possible misinterpretation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#64;Hubird, &amp;#64;Montza:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven't touched the &amp;quot;site design&amp;quot; for almost two years now, and I don't &amp;quot;actively make&amp;quot; anything about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those units probably difficult to remove, but because they're just static images embedded in the page itself, which don't even perform any extra round trip to my own server -- let alone a 3rd party server -- and therefore don't implement any persistent tracking / behavioral stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course the DOM being a bit random doesn't help either, but this picture of an evil and obsessive webmaster &amp;quot;actively&amp;quot; watching subscription authors and &amp;quot;changing site design in an effort to thwart attempts&amp;quot; is quite off base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/forum/viewtopic.php?f=1&amp;amp;t=7356#p45639"&gt;Giorgio Maone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I and several others interpreted this statement to mean that the websites would not be changed in the event that filters were added for the domains, and I therefore committed what would be the first of many rules, reasoning that &amp;quot;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/forum/viewtopic.php?f=1&amp;amp;t=7356#p45663"&gt;if a website is not actively altered I see no reason why EasyList should not filter out all the adverts&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were initially a couple of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/easylist/rev/6eaa4e863a4a"&gt;minor&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/easylist/rev/18aee58644f6"&gt;changes&lt;/a&gt; to the subscription, which were ultimately suggested to have resulted from a lack of testing on the website, as we assumed that the pages would remain static. I further proposed that the filters should be more specific to avoid false positives, a change that was implemented for both &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/easylist/rev/1035c7842ce8"&gt;NoScript.net&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/easylist/rev/4ec885e7bf06"&gt;FlashGot.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we then became increasingly aware that the filters were ineffective when we checked the domains, and therefore subsequently altered the rules on several occasions for both websites (the full &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/easylist/log?rev=noscript.net"&gt;list of revisions for NoScript.net&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/easylist/log?rev=flashgot.net"&gt;list of revisions for FlashGot.net&lt;/a&gt; and are publicly available from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/easylist/"&gt;our repository&lt;/a&gt;). Although we were aware that the website was randomly altered by the server, we all agreed that certain elements of randomness, such as using alternative and altering tag names, was definitely not present when filters were first added for the domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I further discovered from MonztA, an EasyList author and moderator on the Adblock Plus forums, that Giorgio posted anonymously as &amp;quot;Guest&amp;quot; on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/forum/viewtopic.php?t=7356&amp;amp;start=15#p46104"&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/forum/viewtopic.php?f=1&amp;amp;t=7356&amp;amp;start=15#p46106"&gt;occasions&lt;/a&gt; to report issues with the website, something that I consider to be unfair given that he was an involved party in the discussion. It also became apparent that a member of the community was being provided with pages that did not include adverts on Giorgio's domains, making it increasingly difficult to successfully filter the unwanted sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;We eventually decided, having attempted repeatedly to remove the adverts without false positives, that it would be more productive and informative to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/easylist/rev/73a64ca3ae82"&gt;remove the filters specifically for Giorgio's domains from EasyList&lt;/a&gt; and explain the circumstances in a blog post. While I cannot say that this is an unexpected result given past events, I can say that I am disappointed that I could not take Giorgio at his word when he claimed that the &amp;quot;picture of [him as a] webmaster &amp;quot;actively&amp;quot; watching subscription authors and &amp;quot;changing site design in an effort to thwart attempts&amp;quot; is quite off base&amp;quot;. Security depends on the people you trust, as any author of major browser extensions will be aware, and I am certainly less inclined to trust Giorgio after this incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;There aren't really many solutions to the current state of affairs. The use of images encoded and embedded in the stylesheet means that only element hiding rules may be used to collapse the adverts, and the constant randomisation of the domains, in addition to interventions to prevent existing rules from functioning, means that any publicly announced filters are usually invalid within a few hours. Furthermore, at least one member of the advert blocking community who might have been able to assist is unable to view the adverts after his IP address was identified and alternative pages provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="last"&gt;While not an optimum solution, it would appear that the only certain method to avoid Giorgio's adverts is to cease visiting both domains entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: 29/05/2011&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Ares2 claims to have found some safe filters with which do not cause false positives, and I have therefore permitted him to commit these rules to the subscription.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyList"></category><category term="known issues"></category></entry><entry><title>EasyList and EasyPrivacy subscription policies</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2011/03/02/easylist-and-easyprivacy-subscription-policies.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-02T20:15:00+01:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2011-03-02:2011/03/02/easylist-and-easyprivacy-subscription-policies.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There have never previously been formal policies for EasyList and EasyPrivacy, which made it difficult for contributors and, on occasion, authors, to suggest and add filters in a unified manner. This has now changed, with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/en/policy"&gt;the subscription policies&lt;/a&gt; now publicly available on the website. While they may not account for every situation and some areas may be a matter of interpretation, it will help users to understand the decisions made by the EasyList and EasyPrivacy authors and should reduce the number of reports of content that is not covered to the subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would encourage all contributors to view the policies, especially new community members, as they may highlight important decisions taken by the authors; however, these policies are not set in stone and we are perfectly willing to discuss the decisions in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/"&gt;the EasyList forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyList"></category><category term="EasyPrivacy"></category><category term="Website"></category></entry><entry><title>EasyPrivacy Tracking Protection List</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2011/02/10/easyprivacy-tracking-protection-list.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-10T17:00:00+01:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2011-02-10:2011/02/10/easyprivacy-tracking-protection-list.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EasyPrivacy is a comparatively recent subscription in the context of the EasyList project, but it is one that has garnered significant interest recently due to current privacy concerns, which this list of filters was written to address. Yet I had never suspected the possibility of repurposing the subscription not only for a different browser, but also for an entirely different filter processing engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this opportunity presented itself when &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.microsoft.com/"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; recently announced &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/ie/archive/2010/12/07/ie9-and-privacy-introducing-tracking-protection-v8.aspx"&gt;Tracking Protection Lists&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.beautyoftheweb.com/"&gt;Internet Explorer 9&lt;/a&gt;. After some discussion with Microsoft just over a month ago we found that we were able to automatically convert the majority of EasyPrivacy filters to a suitable form for Internet Explorer, and a script has therefore been uploaded to our host server to automate this process every ten minutes. This new subscription variant has been entitled EasyPrivacy Tracking Protection List or, in its abbreviated form, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://easylist-msie.adblockplus.org/easyprivacy.tpl"&gt;EasyPrivacy TPL&lt;/a&gt;, and may be &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ie.microsoft.com/testdrive/Browser/TrackingProtectionLists/Default.html"&gt;installed from Microsoft's Tracking Protection List page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the script that generates the EasyList subscriptions has been updated to include the conversion process from Adblock Plus to Tracking Protection List format and these changes have been &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/easylistcombinations/rev/50f21baafda3"&gt;committed&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/easylistcombinations"&gt;the repository&lt;/a&gt;, from where &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/easylistcombinations/file/tip/combineSubscriptions.py"&gt;combineSubscriptions.py&lt;/a&gt; may be downloaded and used for the automatic conversion of other subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would therefore encourage anyone interested in using the subscription to install the release candidate version of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.beautyoftheweb.com/"&gt;Internet Explorer 9&lt;/a&gt;, a browser that appears to have been significantly improved since the last release, and install &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://easylist-msie.adblockplus.org/easyprivacy.tpl"&gt;EasyPrivacy Tracking Protection List&lt;/a&gt;, which is now &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/#easyprivacytpl"&gt;listed on the homepage&lt;/a&gt;. Any &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://forums.lanik.us/viewforum.php?f=62"&gt;suggestions&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://forums.lanik.us/viewforum.php?f=64"&gt;false positives&lt;/a&gt; should be reported in the respective sections of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://forums.lanik.us/"&gt;the EasyList forums&lt;/a&gt;, which does not require registration in order to post.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyPrivacy"></category><category term="Tracking Protection Lists"></category></entry><entry><title>ABPindo is now an affiliated subscription</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2010/12/23/abpindo-is-now-an-affiliated-subscription.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-12-23T18:44:00+01:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2010-12-23:2010/12/23/abpindo-is-now-an-affiliated-subscription.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://abpindo.blogspot.com/"&gt;ABPindo&lt;/a&gt; has now become officially affiliated with EasyList after considerable updates to the element hiding filers to improve efficiency. The subscription, which has been steadily developed since February of this year, is designed as a supplement for Indonesian-language websites and is now listed on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/"&gt;EasyList homepage&lt;/a&gt;, from where it may be &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://indonesianadblockrules.googlecode.com/hg/subscriptions/abpindo.txt"&gt;viewed&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="abp://subscribe?location=http://indonesianadblockrules.googlecode.com/hg/subscriptions/abpindo.txt&amp;amp;title=ABPindo&amp;amp;requiresLocation=https://easylist-downloads.adblockplus.org/easylist.txt&amp;amp;requiresTitle=EasyList&amp;quot;"&gt;installed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to provide feedback about ABPindo, including reporting adverts or problems, please use the Adblock Plus issue reporter or submit suggestions via the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.kaskus.us/showthread.php?t=3646917"&gt;relevant forum topic&lt;/a&gt;, which requires registration to access and post.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Affiliated filter lists"></category><category term="EasyList"></category></entry><entry><title>Who does anti-Adblock actually affect?</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2010/12/21/who-does-anti-adblock-actually-affect.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-12-21T07:47:00+01:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2010-12-21:2010/12/21/who-does-anti-adblock-actually-affect.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Anti-Adblock scripts, which attempt to identify users of advert-blocking software and limit or, more commonly, disable access to content, appear to have become increasingly prevalent recently. Yet the techniques used to detect unwanted software are by no means infallible, and I have seen, on several occasions, that while they are certainly targeting particular groups of people, this has tended to include many innocent bystanders. I have therefore decided to outline the visitors who I believe are usually affected by such additional website &amp;quot;functionality&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People with scripting disabled&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;It is not uncommon for JavaScript to be disabled for reasons of security, with one of the most used Firefox add-ons, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/722/"&gt;NoScript&lt;/a&gt;, being available specifically for this purpose. As anti-Adblock nearly always requires client scripting in order to detect advert filtration, it can just as easily cause problems for any security-conscious members of the online community &lt;a class="footnote-reference" href="#id2" id="id1"&gt;[*]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People with special software requirements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Not everyone accesses the internet in exactly the same manner; some out of choice, some out of necessity. People in the latter group usually have a disability that prevents them from being able to interpret web pages as provided in standard browsers, and therefore may use alternatives to cater for their needs. However, as anti-Adblock techniques usually assume that there is only one possible display of a page, something that is simply inaccurate given that HTML, by definition, only marks pages rather than precisely defines them, people with customised web browsers may also be prevented from viewing page content. One of the most ludicrous examples that I have encountered is a site aimed at blind people that pointlessly mandates that all images are loaded in order to permit the textual content to be displayed.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People with poor connections to the website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Anti-Adblock techniques usually revolve around loading an item with a name that would usually be blocked by filter subscriptions and subsequently detecting whether or not it is present; however, this relies on the object being immediately available to be scrutinised. There are two reasons why this may not occur: the first is that the client could be using a dial-up internet connection and the second is a reliance on a particular server being constantly available for communicating data, a problem only exacerbated when the item is hosted on a third-party domain. Relying on these two suppositions is extremely risky, as no hosting or internet service provider can guarantee 100% up time or that every connection will be successful.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Search engine spiders&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Search engine spiders usually only record the text of a page, with Google noting that &amp;quot;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.google.com/support/webmasters/bin/answer.py?answer=35769"&gt;fancy features such as JavaScript [mean that] search engine spiders may have trouble crawling your site&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; ; however, requiring every item to be loaded on a domain, something that a bot may not do, means that all that the search engine will record is that advert blocking programs must not be used. This damages any search result rankings applied to the content because there is no relevant text to analyse and could consequently worsen the position of the domain when a particular term is requested.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the above list demonstrates, there are many innocent people who are affected by attempts to implement anti-Adblock on a domain. The irony is that visitors with sufficiently advanced advert-blocking software are usually unaffected by such measures because of the presence of whitelists that protect necessary items and automatically updating subscriptions that distribute alterations negating detection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when you next consider adding anti-Adblock to a website, please first consider you you are actually going to cause problems for: visitors blocking adverts, people with slow internet connections or disabilities, or your own search engine reputation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="docutils footnote" frame="void" id="id2" rules="none"&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;&lt;col class="label" /&gt;&lt;col /&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;
&lt;tbody valign="top"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="label"&gt;&lt;a class="fn-backref" href="#id1"&gt;[*]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Incidentally, some people remove adverts to decrease the number of attack vectors available when visiting a website, and therefore can also fall into the category of &amp;quot;security-conscious&amp;quot; visitors.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</summary><category term="Adblock Plus"></category><category term="known issues"></category></entry><entry><title>An important reminder about adult websites</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2010/12/12/an-important-reminder-about-adult-websites.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-12-12T16:51:00+01:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2010-12-12:2010/12/12/an-important-reminder-about-adult-websites.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The introduction of the Adblock Plus issue reporter has resulted in a significant increase in the number of users who have reported missing adverts or problems on adult domains. These reports have often been met with little to no response for the simple reason that EasyList and EasyPrivacy policy dictates that adult domains are not considered when adding filters to the subscriptions. Adult domains have a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://weis2010.econinfosec.org/papers/session2/weis2010_wondracek.pdf"&gt;purportedly more aggressive style of advertising&lt;/a&gt; than most websites, which would mean that an exceptionally high number of specific filters would be required to remove the unwanted content from domains of this nature. These filters provide little benefit to the majority of users, who would still have to regularly download the larger subscriptions despite never using the rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would therefore recommend that users who regularly visit adult websites install a supplementary subscription that specifically targets domains of this nature, such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="abp://subscribe?location=https%3A%2F%2Fsecure.fanboy.co.nz%2Ffanboy-adult.txt&amp;amp;title=Fanboy's%20Adult%2FDating%20List&amp;amp;requiresLocation=https%3A%2F%2Feasylist-downloads.adblockplus.org%2Feasylist.txt&amp;amp;requiresTitle=EasyList"&gt;Fanboy's Adult/Dating List&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a class="reference external" href="abp://subscribe?location=https%3A%2F%2Fadversity.googlecode.com%2Fhg%2FAdversity-Adult.txt&amp;amp;title=Adversity%20Adult%20List&amp;amp;requiresLocation=https%3A%2F%2Feasylist-downloads.adblockplus.org%2Feasylist.txt&amp;amp;requiresTitle=EasyList"&gt;Adversity Adult List&lt;/a&gt;, both of which are listed in the full list of subscriptions, and report any issues that arise to the respective maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: 30/05/2011&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscription policy on adult websites has been revised; the changes and the reasons for the alterations are explained in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/blog/2011/05/30/announcing-easyadult"&gt;a more recent article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyList"></category><category term="EasyList Germany"></category><category term="EasyList Privacy"></category></entry><entry><title>Bulgarian list is now an affiliated subscription</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2010/12/09/bulgarian-list-is-now-an-affiliated-subscription.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-12-09T21:17:00+01:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2010-12-09:2010/12/09/bulgarian-list-is-now-an-affiliated-subscription.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Alex, the author of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://stanev.org/abp/"&gt;Bulgarian list&lt;/a&gt;, has recently revamped his subscription by updating the filter syntax and checking almost every rule for redundancies. The EasyList authors have been very impressed by his efforts and the resulting subscription, and it has therefore become the first affiliated subscription not to use the EasyList forums. Bulgarian list is now listed on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://easylist.adblockplus.org/#bulgarianlist"&gt;the EasyList homepage&lt;/a&gt;, where it may be &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://stanev.org/abp/adblock_bg.txt"&gt;viewed&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="abp://subscribe?location=http://stanev.org/abp/adblock_bg.txt&amp;amp;title=Bulgarian%20list&amp;amp;requiresLocation=https://easylist-downloads.adblockplus.org/easylist.txt&amp;amp;requiresTitle=EasyList"&gt;added to Adblock Plus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, Bulgarian list has recently become &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://hg.adblockplus.org/subscriptionlist/rev/bb5e701a6e8a"&gt;a recommendation in Adblock Plus&lt;/a&gt;, and will be selected by default for Bulgarian users of the add-on from version 1.3.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to provide feedback about Bulgarian List, including reporting adverts or problems, please use the Adblock Plus issue reporter or submit suggestions via &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://stanev.org/abp/?SendFilters"&gt;the form on Alex's website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Affiliated filter lists"></category><category term="EasyList"></category></entry><entry><title>Wikimedia fundraising banners</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2010/11/16/wikimedia-fundraising-banners.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-11-16T21:20:00+01:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2010-11-16:2010/11/16/wikimedia-fundraising-banners.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is an almost annual contention over the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wikimedia.org/"&gt;Wikimedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/Fundraising_2010"&gt;fundraising banners&lt;/a&gt; that appear on websites including the widely visited &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wikipedia.org/"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; requesting donations. As it is that time of year again, it appears prudent to formally explain the position of subscriptions towards such items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EasyList policy dictates that self promotion is not specifically blocked by the subscriptions, although such items are equally not whitelisted if they happen to be removed by general filters; as the Wikimedia banners are present to inform people about the organisation's own products, they fall into this category. Furthermore, as we actively encourage website owners to request donations from users for financial support as an alternative to placing advertisements on their domain it is hypocritical to subsequently remove them using the subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there have been criticisms of the banners being annoying, this is not a reason for them to be blocked by EasyList. &amp;quot;Annoying&amp;quot; is a subjective quality that is very difficult to define and therefore implement as a fair and unbiased policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that EasyPrivacy blocks tracking on the domains with the filter &lt;strong&gt;||bits.wikimedia.org/geoiplookup&lt;/strong&gt;, a rule that incidentally removes the banners. This filter is present to prevent the collection of personal data rather to fulfil than the additional purpose of removing the site notices that ultimately appears to have been served.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to block the Wikimedia fundraising notice, just add the following rule to your &amp;quot;Custom filters&amp;quot; in Adblock Plus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;||wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:BannerLoader?$domain=wikipedia.org&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who want to donate money to Wikimedia should do so on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Donate"&gt;their donations page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="known issues"></category><category term="EasyList"></category><category term="EasyPrivacy"></category></entry><entry><title>Filter subscriptions and important internet transactions</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2010/10/29/filter-subscriptions-and-important-internet-transactions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-10-29T19:36:00+02:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2010-10-29:2010/10/29/filter-subscriptions-and-important-internet-transactions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Filter subscriptions can occasionally cause problems on websites, with issues ranging from text failing to display to videos not playing. However, issues are a lot more serious if they occur on websites where important transactions take place, such as banking, shopping, or booking travel arrangements, where a blocked item has the potential to prevent an order from being received. Furthermore, it should be expected that there is a higher incidences of false positives on, for example, shopping sites. On domains of this nature people usually want to see adverts, as the promotions could be what is attempting to be purchased, and want to be tracked to ensure that the company receives an order correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only way that it can be guaranteed that an advert-blocker does not cause issues is by disabling it when making an important transaction. If using the Adblock Plus add-on this can be achieved by middle-clicking on the extension icon in the browser to disable it, with the same action being used to revert to the original state. Alternatively, domains visited regularly may be protected by the Adblock Plus filter &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#64;&amp;#64;||example.com^document&lt;/strong&gt;, where &lt;strong&gt;example.com&lt;/strong&gt; is the name of the important website. Although this may mean that users have to temporarily endure advertisements and tracking, the guarantee that an important order has been received correctly is something much more important.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="known issues"></category></entry><entry><title>Affiliated subscriptions</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2010/10/10/affiliated-subscriptions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-10-10T10:10:00+02:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2010-10-10:2010/10/10/affiliated-subscriptions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new website currently lists considerably fewer external subscriptions than it once did. This is as a result of a review that I have carried of the Adblock Plus recommended subscriptions in which I was somewhat surprised to discover that several contained deprecated syntax and inefficient filters, therefore rendering them unsuitable for the homepage. The most common issues that I noticed were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use of simplified element syntax&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Simplified element syntax is delineated by the use of just one hash symbol (&amp;quot;#&amp;quot;) in the rule and is currently present in Adblock Plus for reasons of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/en/filters#elemhide_simplified"&gt;backwards compatibility only&lt;/a&gt;. It has been suggested that support for rules of this type may be removed at some point in the future, which further necessitates that affiliated subscriptions use the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/en/filters#elemhide"&gt;more recent and efficient syntax for element hiding&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Domains not clearly indicated&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Since &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/releases/adblock-plus-11-released"&gt;the Adblock Plus 1.1 release&lt;/a&gt; over a year ago, the beginning of a domain name may be indicated by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/en/filters#anchors"&gt;two vertical bars (&amp;quot;||&amp;quot;)&lt;/a&gt; and the end by the use of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/en/filters#separators"&gt;a caret separator character (&amp;quot;^&amp;quot;)&lt;/a&gt;. This syntax reduces the risk of false positives appearing and it is therefore highly advisable that it is implemented in filter subscriptions.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inefficient element hiding rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;I have noticed that element hiding rules are seldom implemented efficiently in existing subscriptions, which slows down the speed at which Adblock Plus may process the lists. There are two ways in which filters may be optimised: the tag name, such as &amp;quot;div&amp;quot;, may be removed from filters only specifying the id (&amp;quot;###&amp;quot;) or the class (&amp;quot;##.&amp;quot;) and only one class, indicated by the presence of a full stop (&amp;quot;.&amp;quot;), need be referenced. Therefore &lt;strong&gt;example.com##div.box.advert&lt;/strong&gt; may have the unnecessary class removed (&lt;strong&gt;example.com##div.advert&lt;/strong&gt;) and the tag not specified (&lt;strong&gt;example.com##.advert&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscriptions contain redundant filters, either when used alone or as a supplement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Subscriptions should not contain multiple filters that are logically redundant, as this unnecessarily increases the size of a supplement and the complexity of maintaining it. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://arestwo.org/famlam/redundantRuleChecker.html"&gt;Famlam's redundancy checker&lt;/a&gt; enables anyone to check lists of filters to verify that no more rules are present than need to be.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No sections present in the subscription&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Although not an issue that would prevent a subscription from being listed on the EasyList website, it is highly recommended that filters are sorted in a logical order with sections to delineate the purpose of particular rules. This makes the supplement far easier to both maintain and adjust, as rules may be easily found and altered.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If authors would like their filter subscription to be evaluated for the website they should check that all of the above issues are not present in their subscription and then &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:easylist.blog&amp;#64;gmail.com"&gt;e-mail me&lt;/a&gt; with a request that their list be considered. It is expected that the subscription should already be listed &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/en/subscriptions"&gt;on the Adblock Plus website&lt;/a&gt;, as this is the origin of all the essential data about the filter list; if not &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:subscriptionlist&amp;#64;adblockplus.org"&gt;an e-mail should be sent&lt;/a&gt; to request that this page updated first.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Affiliated filter lists"></category><category term="Website"></category></entry><entry><title>How to deal with unwanted items</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2010/10/02/how-to-deal-with-unwanted-items.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-10-02T07:36:00+02:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2010-10-02:2010/10/02/how-to-deal-with-unwanted-items.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If users should encounter unwanted items when using Adblock Plus it is extremely easy to report and resolve the issue with the assistance of the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first recommended response is to update all subscriptions used, which may be accomplished by right-clicking the Adblock Plus logo in the top right-hand corner of the browser, selecting &amp;quot;Preferences...&amp;quot; and then activating the &amp;quot;Filters&amp;quot; menu followed by the option &amp;quot;Update all subscriptions&amp;quot;. If there are no subscriptions installed, then users are strongly advised to select one; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/en/subscriptions"&gt;a full list of possibilities is available at the Adblock Plus website&lt;/a&gt;. The problematic page should then be loaded or refreshed. If the issue is resolved as a result of this command it means that the authors are already aware of the content encountered and have updated the subscription to match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the unwanted content remains, it is advisable to submit a report directly to the authors about the encountered item, as this will ensure that the issue is resolved for all users of the subscription and that any additional assistance necessary may be easily provided by the community. It is also hassle-free, as both the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://forums.lanik.us/"&gt;EasyList&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://adblockplus.org/forum/"&gt;Adblock Plus forums&lt;/a&gt; do not require registration to post, and there is the additional option of &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:easylist.subscription&amp;#64;gmail.com"&gt;contacting the EasyList authors via e-mail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are, however, crucial pieces of information that are needed to quickly and effectively deal with the suggestions; these are listed below in order of priority. Too much data is always preferable to too little; authors may not receive the same content because of geographical restrictions, and it is therefore beneficial to have all the information about the unwanted content provided as opposed to having to enquire further about specific aspects of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class="first docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A specific link to the problematic page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first last"&gt;The critical bit of information that is required in a report is the address of the website that is affected, as this allows authors to personally examine the page and attempt to reproduce the issue. It is also important that this link is as specific as possible and points to the exact location where filters are needed, as this prevents authors from needlessly exploring domains in the hope that they can locate the subject of the report. In many instances a specific link to a problematic page is all that is required to resolve an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class="first docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Addresses of the unwanted items&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Adblock Plus and other similar pieces of software remove unwanted items by checking whether the location of an item matches the list of forbidden content dictated by the subscription. It is therefore easier to add filters if the exact addresses are provided by the reporter. The items are listed in the Adblock Plus blockable items window, which may be opened by right-clicking the icon in the top left-hand corner of the browser and selecting the menu option &amp;quot;Open blockable items&amp;quot;. If the exact reference to the content cannot be discerned, then selecting everything listed and copying it into a report is more useful than having no information about the addresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class="first docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The location of the unwanted content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Sometimes even a specific link to a page is not enough to find the unwanted content, and it is therefore advisable that reports either explain where it is or provide a screenshot demonstrating the location. This is especially useful if there are unblocked text adverts, as they will not be listed as blockable items because they are a part of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class="first docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom filters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first last"&gt;If any rules have been created that successfully remove some or all of the unwanted content from the page it is always beneficial if suggested strings are provided; however, as it is possible that an author may choose to filter content in a slightly different manner to that proposed the full addresses of unwanted content are usually more useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;dl class="first docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Occasionally, issues may arise as a result of a unique set-up. It is therefore beneficial if the following information is provided in the report:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="last simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Active subscription names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adblock Plus version or equivalent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser name and version&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it is important that users are available to answer any queries or to clarify aspects of the account. If an issue cannot be replicated then it is possible that all the work put into a report will be wasted because the person experiencing the issue is unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="EasyList"></category><category term="EasyList Germany"></category><category term="EasyList Privacy"></category></entry><entry><title>Welcome to the new EasyList website</title><link href="https://easylist.github.io/2010/08/31/welcome-to-the-new-easylist-website.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-08-31T15:45:00+02:00</published><author><name>Michael</name></author><id>tag:easylist.github.io,2010-08-31:2010/08/31/welcome-to-the-new-easylist-website.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EasyList website has been practically dormant for over a year, providing inaccurate information about the project and using a now superseded method of styling pages. The sub-domain has therefore been completely revamped over the summer and now contains entirely new content and coding. Among the many additions are a custom logo designed by &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://peewee1002.co.uk/"&gt;Peewee&lt;/a&gt;, German translations of the primary pages provided by MonztA, and EasyBlog. These changes permit greater communication and discussion with the community and, most importantly, end users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please let us know what you think of the new design in the comments section of the blog or by contacting the project at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:easylist.blog&amp;#64;gmail.com"&gt;new e-mail address specifically for website feedback&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="Website"></category></entry></feed>